Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
Where's Asuka?
She's already left. It would seem that
she's determined not to see me.
Why?
Shinji, I guess you're still too young
to understand a woman's feelings.
Well...
By the way...
Go ahead.
Is the rumor that Unit 04 went missing true?
I heard that there was some kind
of accident, and it exploded.
Yes, it's true.
Unit 04 vanished, along with
the Second Branch of Nerv.
It happened while they were
testing the S2 engine.
But don't worry, we'll be all right here.
All three of our Evas are functioning properly.
And we have a crack team of pilots and staff.
But I heard that Unit 03 is being
brought here from America.
You're performing the activation tests
at Matsushiro, aren't you?
I'll be out for four days or so,
but Kaji will be taking care of you two,
so don't worry.
But what about the test?
Ritsuko will be there as well, after all.
There won't be any problems.
But what about the pilot?
Well, about the pilot...
Yes?
Good morning!
I've come today with a request, Major Katsuragi!
Please! Make me the pilot
for Evangelion Unit 03!
EPISODE 18
SELECTION
OF LIFE
So, Shinji doesn't know yet?
Finding the right time to tell him...
I'm scared.
Sometimes I just can't tell
what the heck he's thinking.
Pull yourself together.
You're the one who volunteered
to be his guardian.
I know, but...
So when are you calling in the pilot?
I think that'll be tomorrow.
There are a lot of things to prep, after all.
He might tell Shinji himself.
I don't think so.
He wasn't enthused enough
to be bragging about it.
Getting his sister transferred to
our hospital here at Headquarters
was the one condition he gave.
Man, Miss Misato sure can be cold.
I'm number one when it comes to enthusiasm,
so she could at least use me,
even if it's just as a backup.
Right, Toji?
What happened? You left before me,
but you're awfully late.
What, no marital spat today?
I just didn't want to see your ugly faces!
You three damn stooges!
Now, time to eat!
Hey, where's Toji?
He's gone.
Without even eating lunch? Him?
That's impossible.
He's been acting odd lately, hasn't he?
Suzuhara...
Oh, Ayanami, if you're lookin' for Shinji,
he ain't here.
You know 'bout me, don't you?
Seems Sohryu knows too.
So Shinji's the only one who doesn't know.
You don't usually care 'bout people.
Really? I'm not sure I understand.
The one you care about's Shinji.
Do I?
You may be right.
Yeah, you do.
Hikari!
Let's have lunch!
Two hours late, and then, finally, he arrives.
He's the first guy to ever make me
wait this long.
Yeah, because you never waited for the guy
when you were dating, right?
And so this was the so-called Second Impact.
At that time I was living in a place
called Nebukawa,
but the rising water levels caused
by the melting of Antarctica
have submerged it beneath the sea.
Sorry, transfer student,
but I've gotta beat you up!
I won't feel right until I've smacked you.
I'm sorry, Asuka. You always
walk home with Ikari.
Forget it. The only reason I'm with Shinji
is because of work.
And I don't feel like seeing him today anyway.
This is about Suzuhara, isn't it?
Yes. You could tell?
It's obvious.
The three stooges are about
the only ones who don't see it.
But Ikari seems naïve.
Actually, he's the most dense of them all.
And he's an idiot to boot.
He doesn't know how to relate to people.
Really?
I think Suzuhara might like Miss Ayanami.
Suzuhara does?! Miss Perfect?!
They seemed to be getting along during lunch.
Don't worry, Hikari. There's no way.
She's a million times denser than Shinji is
about relating to people!
Really?
Really!
Can I ask you one thing?
What?
What do you see in that hot-headed stooge?
His kindness...
Come to think of it...
Kaji sure spends a lot of time in the tub.
I wonder who's going to pilot Unit 03?
You mean you haven't heard yet?
Who is it?
I don't know.
That was refreshing!
What? Are you two fighting again?
You guys are hopeless.
Are you two always like this
when Katsuragi's gone?
No!
I get to spend the night with you, after all,
so I'd love to be all happy and smiling.
But I can't do it tonight. I just can't.
I understand. Let's go to bed.
Going to bed early is the best thing
for these situations.
Are you asleep yet, Kaji?
No, not yet.
What's my father like?
Well, that came out of nowhere.
I thought you'd ask about Katsuragi.
Because it seems like you're
always with my father.
It's the Vice Commander who's always with him.
Have you been asking around
about your father?
Because I haven't been around him much.
So you don't really know him?
But I've learned a lot about him lately.
About his work, about my mother, so...
You're wrong there. You only
believe that you've learned.
People can't understand others completely.
Who knows if you can even
understand yourself?
Understanding each other one hundred percent
is impossible.
Of course, that's why we spend so much time
trying to understand ourselves and others.
That's what makes life so interesting.
Is that also true for you and Miss Misato?
The word we use for "she" literally
means "the woman far away".
To us, women will always be
on the distant shore.
Basically, there's a river dividing men and
women, deeper and wider than the ocean.
I don't understand adults.
T minus 300 minutes to Unit 03 activation test.
TEST SITE 2, MATSUHIRO
Main power supply, no problems.
TEMPORARY UNDERGROUND CAGE (UNMANNED)
Second apoptosis is nominal.
SAME SURFACE FACILITY
Coolant systems are normal in all sectors.
Repairs to left arm crimp lock completed.
EVA UNIT-03 ACTIVATION EXPERIMENT
INTEGRATED CONTROL POSITION
Roger. Team B, commence operation.
ON BOARD CENTRAL GENERAL
COMMAND VEHICLE
No problems detected in
the data link to Unit 01.
It could even go into combat as is.
Really? That's nice.
Now that was a half-hearted reply.
You know, once this unit is cleared for duty,
it'll be assigned directly under your command.
The exclusive control of four Evas...
If you wanted to, you could destroy the world.
Have you told Shinji yet?
I will when the test is over.
The Fourth Child has arrived.
Second squad, begin readying
the entry vehicle immediately.
He's not here yet, is he, Asuka?
He may not be coming today.
I thought we might finally eat together today...
Do you want this?
Unit 03's already in Japan, isn't it?
Yeah, I think it got here yesterday.
Must be nice. I wonder who's going to pilot it?
Maybe it's Toji? He's absent today, after all.
No way!
Entry plug fixed in place.
Initiating first connection.
Transmitting pulse.
Graph readout is normal.
Checklist cleared up to 1350.
No problems found in initial contact phase.
Roger. Shift the operation to phase two.
All nerve links are normal.
Checklist cleared up to 2550.
All harmonics are normal.
We are now exceeding the absolute border.
Abort the test! Break the circuit!
No good! High energy readings
detected in body!
Impossible!
An Angel?!
An explosion has occurred in Matsushiro.
Damage level unknown.
Send the rescue squad and the Third Troop.
Take care of it before the SSDF gets involved.
Roger.
Movement of an unidentified object
detected at the site.
Pattern is orange. We can't
confirm it to be an Angel.
Go to battle stations, Level One.
All personnel, battle stations, Level One.
Prepare for ground combat.
Launch all Eva units!
Dispatch immediately to intercept locations.
Air transport is scheduled to go in twenty.
An accident in Matsushiro?!
No way! Then, are Miss Misato
and the others okay?!
We can't contact them yet.
No way. What will we do?
What are you blubbering about?!
Worrying about them right now
won't get us anywhere!
But how can we fight the Angel by ourselves?
Commander Ikari is taking direct command now.
My father is?
We have a visual of the target at Mt. Nobe.
Transferring to main monitor.
As I thought...
Transmit the abort signal.
Force eject the entry plug.
Not working. Neither abort signal
nor plug ejection code accepted.
What about the pilot?
We still have respiratory and cardiac
response, but he's probably...
Evangelion Unit 03 will be
abandoned at this time.
It will be designated as the Thirteenth Angel.
But, Sir!
Deploy the battle line at Mt. Nobe as planned.
Destroy the target.
Target is approaching.
All units prepare for ground combat.
No way!
An Angel? Is that an Angel?!
Correct, that is the target.
You said that this is the target,
but it's an Eva, isn't it?!
But that's...
How could it have been taken over by an Angel?
I wonder if it's piloted by a human too?
A child our age?
You still don't know?! The pilot of Unit 03 is...
Asuka?
Asuka?!
Eva Unit 02 has gone silent!
The pilot has ejected. Recovery squad
is heading for retrieval.
Target is moving towards Unit 00!
Rei, avoid close range combat
and stop the target.
I'm sending Unit 01 over now.
Roger.
He's in there.
The Angel is invading Unit 00's left arm.
The nerve systems are being corrupted.
Sever the left arm. Quickly!
But if we don't cut the neural connections first...
Sever it.
Yes, Sir.
Unit 00 is severely damaged.
The pilot is wounded.
No way...
The target is approaching you.
It will contact you in twenty.
You must destroy it.
But this target is...
Isn't there a person in there?
Another child my own age.
An entry plug!
There is a person in there, just as I thought.
Problems in life support!
The pilot's in danger!
Not good! Cut the synch rate to 60%!
Wait!
But Ikari, at this rate, the pilot will die.
Shinji, why don't you fight?
But there's a person in there, Father!
Irrelevant! It is an Angel! Our enemy!
But... but I can't!
I've got to save them! I can't just kill somebody!
You'll die.
I don't care! It's better than killing someone!
Never mind! Cut all synchronization
between the pilot and Unit 01.
Cut it?
Correct. Switch the control circuit
to the dummy plug.
But the dummy system still has
a lot of problems,
and without Dr. Akagi's approval...
It'll be of more use than the pilot. Do it!
Yes, Sir.
What is this?
What did you do, Father?!
Reception of the signal, confirmed.
Control system switch is complete.
All nerves linked directly to the dummy system.
32.8% of Emotional Elements are unclear.
They can't be monitored.
Irrelevant. Release the system.
Commence attack.
This is the power of the dummy plug?
System status nominal.
Gain still increasing.
Stop it!
Father, stop! Stop doing this!
Damn! Stop!
Stop it! Stop it! Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
Stop!
STOP!
Eva Unit 03, no, I mean,
the target is completely silent.
I'll make this.
Kodama, Nozomi, and I...
This recipe is for four.
I wonder if he'll eat it tomorrow?
We've found a survivor over here too!
He's still breathing!
Third squad, erase 807 data
as soon as possible.
Send help right away!
Second squad, please hurry and check
for survivors in the linear block.
Am I still alive?
Kaji?
You were lucky, Katsuragi.
Where's Ritsuko?
Don't worry.
She wasn't hurt as bad as you.
I see.
What about Eva Unit 03?
It was apparently destroyed,
as an Angel, by Unit 01.
I... I haven't told Shinji anything.
Shinji...
Miss Misato, so you're all right?
I...
I'm sorry.
I had something important to tell you, but...
Miss Misato, I...
I killed...
It was my father...
I begged him to stop, but...
Shinji, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Report from the entry plug recovery team.
The pilot's life signs are confirmed.
He's alive?!
Unit 03's pilot is...
The Fourth Child is...
Toji?
Shinji?
Shinji?!
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
Shinji finally, of his own will,
quits as an Eva pilot.
But regardless of his decision, the strongest of
the Angels attacks, giving rise to a new tragedy.
Next time: "A Man's Battle"
A MAN'S BATTLE